Finding Aid for the Ed Ainsworth Papers LSC.0405
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ed Ainsworth papers
1945-1968
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ainsworth, Ed
LSC.0405
43.0 Linear Feet (86 boxes and 13 oversize boxes)
Edward Maddin Ainsworth (1902-1968) worked for the Los Angeles Times as a copyreader in 1924. He progressed from city editor to state editor, editorial page editor, assistant to the managing editor, and eventually became a columnist. He also wrote several books on California and the West and contributed to various magazines. The collection consists of literary manuscripts, correspondence, articles, clippings, books, and photographs related to Ainsworth's career as a writer and journalist.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Katie Ainsworth, 1981-82.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994621543606533
Biography
Edward Maddin Ainsworth was born in 1902 in Waco, Texas; attended Texas A & M and UCLA; worked for newspapers in Waco, Texas, San Pedro and Bakersfield, California, and Atlanta, Georgia, before coming to work at the Los Angeles Times as a copyreader in 1924; progressed from city editor to state editor, editorial page editor, assistant to the managing editor, and eventually became a columnist; author of column, On the Move; member, Board of Governors, Los Angeles County Museum; member, Zamorano Club, Death Valley 49'ers, and E Clampus Vitus; wrote several books on California and the West and also contributed to various magazines; married Katherine Lake, chief librarian in Monrovia, California, 1931; died in 1968.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of literary manuscripts, correspondence, articles, clippings, books, and photographs related to Ainsworth's career as a writer and journalist. Writings focus primarily on California and the West, including the Fallbrook case, smog, water problems, Leo Carillo, and former mayor of Los Angeles Sam Yorty. Some of Ainsworth's titles in the collection include: Eagles Fly West, California Jubilee, Question of Smog in Southern California, Maverick Mayor, Sand Dune Sanctuary, Beckoning Desert, The Cowboy in Art, Sapphires Are Forever, California Desert, and Painters of the Desert.
Related Material
Katherine Ainsworth Papers (Collection 1395). Available at the Library Special Collections, UCLA.
West (U.S.) -- History.; Western stories.; Historians -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Journalists -- California -- Los Angeles -- Archives.; Los Angeles (Calif.) -- History.; Los Angeles Times (Firm); Ainsworth, Ed, 1902-1968--Archives.
- Register of Books, Manuscripts and Ephemera
  - Eagles Fly West. Published by Macmillan, New York, 1947.; (Typescript, 790 leaves. Boxed in black, cloth slipcase) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    With extensive holograph corrections and additions.
  - Eagles Fly West., (Typescript, 1146 leaves. In three, blue, cardboard boxes) (Box 3, Box 4)
    Later draft with extensive holograph corrections and additions.
  - Eagles Fly West., (172pp., in one envelope) (Box 2)
    Galley proof with occasional corrections.
    General note
    Title page inscribed in ink: To/UCLA Library/ Ed Ainsworth/September 25, 1947.
  - Eagles Fly West., (Copy of book in dust wrapper) (Box 4)
    Inscribed first leaf reads: To/University of California Library-/this account of the romantic /early days of California/when a State was a-borning./Sincerely,/Ed Ainsworth.
  - Eagles Fly West., (In folder) (Box 2)
    Original water color design for dust wrapper by Clyde Forsythe, with pencil notations for printing.
    Inscribed in ink at bottom by artist, September 30, 1947.
  - California Jubilee. Los Angeles: Murray & Gee, Incorporated, 1948.; (Typescript in wine, cloth slipcase. 272pp.) (Box 2)
    With minor corrections.
    Original title: Sentimental Serenade.
  - Ephemera. Materials re Eagles Fly West and California Jubilee., (5 items, in folder) (Box 2)
    Photographs, printed matter, etc.
  - Miscellaneous material concerning Southern California and the Los Angeles Times, and California State Polytechnic College, San Luis Obispo. (Box 5, Box 6)
  - The Fallbrook Case, ca., 1950-1960. (Box 7, Box 8, Box 9, Box 10, Box 11)
  - The Question of Smog in Southern California, ca., 1945-1960. (Box 12, Box 13, Box 14, Box 15, Box 16, Box 17, Box 18, Box 19, Box 20)
  - The Fallbrook Case. (Box 85, Box 86)
  - General File (Box 21, Box 22, Box 23, Box 24, Box 25, Box 26, Box 27, Box 28, Box 29, Box 30, Box 31, Box 32, Box 33, Box 34, Box 35, Box 36, Box 37, Box 38, Box 39)
    Containing newsletters, newspapers, clippings, legal briefs, books, pamphlets, mimeographed and printed reports, speeches, special news releases, correspondence and photos. Printed material predominates.
    File covers a wide variety of subjects, most relating to California and the Southwest.
    - Adeleno - BYJAC News. (Box 21)
    - Cachuma Dam - Condors. (Box 22)
    - Copyrights - El Monte. (Box 23)
    - Engle - India Village. (Box 24)
    - Infantile Paralysis - Abraham Lincoln. (Box 25)
    - Long Beach (Tidelands Correspondence) - Lummis House. (Box 26)
    - Long Beach Tidelands - Mining. (Box 27)
    - Mining Laws - Music Center. (Box 28)
    - Music Center - Oil. (Box 29)
    - Ojai - Pasadena. (Box 30)
    - Passports - Pulitzer prizes. (Box 31)
    - Radio - Reclamation Bureau. (Box 32)
    - Recovery Plans - Richfield Oil. (Box 33)
    - Richfield Oil - San Andreas Fault. (Box 34)
    - San Diego Aqueduct - State vs. Cities. (Box 35)
    - Steel - Traffic. (Box 36)
    - Trinity County - Wagner Act. (Box 37)
    - Wallace - Women. (Box 38)
    - Yorty - Western Water News, 1949-1960. (Box 39)
      * Material acquired August 29, 1967.
  - General file. (Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43, Box 44, Box 45, Box 46, Box 47, Box 48, Box 49, Box 50, Box 51, Box 52, Box 53, Box 54, Box 55, Box 56, Box 57, Box 58)
    Containing newsletters, newspapers, clippings, legal briefs, books, pamphlets, mimeographed and printed reports, speeches, special news releases, correspondence and photos pertaining to water resources.
    - Feather River Project, 1955-1960 (Box 40, Box 41, Box 42, Box 43)
      - 1955. (Box 40)
      - 1956-1957. (Box 41)
      - 1958-1960. (Box 42)
      - General. (Box 43)
    - Colorado River, 1955-1960. (Box 44)
    - Colorado River--Central Arizona Project, 1956-1960. (Box 45)
    - Colorado River Association, 1956-1960. (Box 45)
    - Kern County Water Association, 1956-1960. (Box 45)
    - San Luis Reservoir Project, 1956-1960. (Box 45)
    - Central Valley Project, 1948-1960. (Box 45)
    - California water--general, 1953-1955. (Box 47)
    - California water--general, 1955-1957. (Box 48)
    - California State Legislation, 1957. (Box 49)
    - Metropolitan Water District; Los Angeles Department of Water and Power; Water News, Hi-Lights, 1958-1961. (Box 50)
    - National water issues; Current water file, 1959-1960. (Box 51)
    - Local water problems in Trinity, Ventura and Alpine Counties, San Diego, San Gabriel, Malibu, Fallbrook, the Klammath River, Delta, Gila Dam, Glen Canyon Dam. (Box 52)
    - Clippings, newspapers, California water problems. (Box 53)
    - Miscellaneous papers, pamphlets, correspondence. (Box 54, Box 55, Box 56)
    - Water articles by Edward Ainsworth. (Box 57)
    - Water articles by sundry authors. (Box 58)
    - Feather River Project Report; Oroville. (Box 99)
      Formerly an unmarked package.
    - Dam Report. (Box 99)
  - Biography of Leo Carillo, by E.M. Ainsworth., (Typescript) (Box 87)
    With holograph corrections.
- Books, Manuscripts, Correspondence & Ephemera Files
  (Added by AC, May 1981)
  - Books and other Writings
    - Cowboy in Art., (Typed carbon copy) (Box 59)
      Manuscript with handwritten corrections.
    - Maverick Mayor: a biography of Sam Yorty, Mayor of Los Angeles., (Copy of book) (Box 59)
      Also, gallery proofs.
      Also, correspondence & papers, including original letters from Yorty.
    - Maverick Mayor..., (Manuscript, typed) (Box 60)
      With handwritten corrections.
      Also, related papers & photographs.
    - Clippings of feature stories. (Box 61, Box 62)
    - Sand Dune Sanctuary., (Typed manuscript) (Box 62)
      Also, related correspondence & papers.
    - The Beckoning Desert., (Copy of book) (Box 62)
      Also, related correspondence.
    - The California Story., (Photocopy) (Box 62)
      Typed manuscript and related papers.
  - Ephemera Files
    - Adobes - California Centennial. (Box 63)
    - California Constitution - Communism, Los Angeles. (Box 64)
    - Council of California Growers - Oskar J. Hansen. (Box 65)
    - India - Mexico. (Box 66)
    - Miscellaneous California problems - Overland Mail Centennial. (Box 67)
      Includes Navajo Indians.
    - Palm Springs Railway - Water. (Box 68)
      Includes Un-American activities.
    - Yuma Test Station. (Box 69)
  - Correspondence Files
    - A - E. (Box 69)
    - Engle, Clair - Jordan Frank [M]. (Box 70)
      Includes Erle Stanley Gardner, Stanley High & Frank Morrill Jordan.
    - K - Museum, Los Angeles County. (Box 71)
      Includes Dana & Ginger Lamb, with photographs & Harold Woodworth Kennedy, with copy speeches.
    - Navajos - S. (Box 72)
      Includes Judge William J. Palmer.
    - Sellers, Clark - Z. (Box 73)
    - Ephemera, mostly maps & tourist guides to Spain. (Box 74)
    - Ephemera relating to Los Angeles. (Box 88)
- Register of Books, Manuscripts and Ephemera
  - Biographical and Photographic Material for Cowboy in Art
    - Bartlett, Gray. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Beeler, Joe. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Beery, Noah. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Bender, Bill. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Birchin, Dorcas Hayne. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Borrin, Ed. (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Boren, Jim. (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Bramlet, James E. (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Bugbee, H.D. (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Chappell, Bill. (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Cherkas, Constantine. (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Delano, Gerard Curtis. (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - De Yong, Joe. (Box 75, Folder 13)
    - Dick, George. (Box 75, Folder 14)
    - Dickinson, Darol Frank. (Box 75, Folder 15)
    - Dixon, Maynard. (Box 75, Folder 16)
    - Donahue, Vick. (Box 75, Folder 17)
    - Dunton, W. Herbert (contains group pictures). (Box 75, Folder 18)
    - Dye, Charles. (Box 75, Folder 19)
    - Echohawk, Brumme. (Box 75, Folder 20)
    - Eggenhoffer, Nick. (Box 75, Folder 21)
    - Ellsworth, Clarence. (Box 75, Folder 22)
    - Fellows, Fred. (Box 75, Folder 23)
    - Firfires, Nicholas. (Box 75, Folder 24)
    - Fraser, James Earl. (Box 75, Folder 25)
    - Free, John D. (Box 75, Folder 26)
    - Freeman, Bill. (Box 75, Folder 27)
    - Gomez, Mark Antonio (Tony). (Box 75, Folder 28)
    - Hall, William. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Hampton, Bill. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Hampton, John W. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Hansen. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Harmon, Fred. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Harvey, Gerald. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Hilton, John. (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Hoffman, Frank B. (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - Hopkins, Harold. (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Hunt, Wayne. (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Jackson, Harry. (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Johnson, Harvey. (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Kittelson, John Henry. (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Klinker, Orpha. (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Lee, Robert M. (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - Koerner, W.H.D. (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Larue, Walt. (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - Lee, Bob. (Box 76, Folder 18)
    - Lindneux, Robert. (Box 76, Folder 19)
    - Long, Stanley. (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - Lougheed, Robert. (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - McGrew, Brownell. (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Martinez, Peter Paul. (Box 76, Folder 23)
    - Marks, George B. (Box 76, Folder 24)
    - Kirk, Martin. (Box 76, Folder 25)
    - Meigs, John. (Box 76, Folder 26)
    - Meyers, Robert. (Box 76, Folder 27)
    - Morris, Ernest. (Box 76, Folder 28)
    - Moyers, William. (Box 76, Folder 29)
    - Paxson, Edgar Samuel. (Box 76, Folder 30)
    - Phippen, George. (Box 76, Folder 31)
    - Powell, Ace L. (Box 76, Folder 32)
    - Price, C.S. (Box 76, Folder 33)
    - Proctor, Alexander Phimister. (Box 76, Folder 34)
    - Pruitt, A. Kelly. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Quigley, Edward B. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Ralston, J.K. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Reaugh, Frank. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Reed, Marjorie. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Remington, Frederic. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Reynolds, James. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Reynolds, Chang. (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Rishell, Robert. (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Roberts, Jack. (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Rockwell, Norman. (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Rossi, Paul R. (director of Thomas Gilcrease Institute of American Art in Tulsa, Oklahoma). (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Russell Charles Martin. (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Ryan, Tom. (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Salisbury, Paul. (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Santel, Ross. (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Schreyvogel, Charles. (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Schwiering, O. Conrad. (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Sedwick, Frances. (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Seltzer, A. (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Shebl, Joseph J., M.D. (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Sherman, Lenore. (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Snidow Gordon E. (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Speed, W. Grant. (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Stahley, Joseph. (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Steele, Sandra. (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Stefan, Ross. (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Strathearn, Bert. (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Swanson, J.N. (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - Thomas, Bernard P. (Box 77, Folder 30)
    - Tonk, Ernest. (Box 77, Folder 31)
    - Van Soelen, Theodore. (Box 77, Folder 32)
    - Von Schmidt, Harold. (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Wagoner, Robert. (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Walker, J. (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Warren, Melvin C. (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Wheeler, Hughlette (Tex). (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Williams, J.R. (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - Wingate, Curtis D. (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Worlds, Clint. (Box 77, Folder 40)
  - Additional Material for Cowboys in Art
    - Mexican Charro material. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Exhibition catalogs, clippings on Western Art. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Aztec Art--photographs, Mexican primitives--slides. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Cattle Drive Art, Sepulveda Art. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Addresses and miscellaneous information on Cowboy Artists. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Signatures and Brands. (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Carbon copy of part of Cowboy in Art. (Box 78, Folder 6-7)
      (See also: Box 59 and 79)
    - Galleys of part of Cowboy in Art. (Box 78, Folder 8-9)
    - Manuscript of Cowboy in Art., Carbon copy with handwritten corrections. (Box 79, Folder 1-2)
      (See Also: Box 59 & 78)
    - Notes for Cowboy in Art. (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Tidelands Controversy
    - Agreement with Board of Harbor Commissioners of the City of Long Beach to produce 261 2 minutes commercial Kodachrome motion pictures depicting conflict about tidelands submerged lands owned by City of Long Beach., (2 copies) (Box 79, Folder 4)
      (See also: Boxes 7--11 and oversize packages 1 and 2)
    - Correspondence on production of film called Freedom's Shores. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Expenses connected with film production. (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Shooting script outline of Freedom's Shores. (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Script of Freedom's Shores., 7 carbon copies) (Box 79, Folder 8)
      Some of the scripts with handwritten corrections.
      (See also: oversize package 18)
    - Miscellaneous and only partly numbered pages of script entitled Terrible Tide., (Carbon copies) (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Questions to be asked in interview with Congressman Clair Engle, October 6, 1952.; (Carbon copies) (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Harry and James Kazanjan
    - Harry and James Kazanjan, Jewelers. (Box 80)
    - Brothers Kazanjan. (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Clippings and printed material.
    - Photographs and printed material. (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, information on precious stones and stonecutters, African photographs, letters, 1956-1967. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Discussion of the chapter sequence of Sapphires Are Forever by Ed Ainsworth, undated.; (Typescript) (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Story Discusion of Sapphires are Forever, undated.; (Typescript) (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Sapphires Are Forever, Notes., (Carbon copy of part of typescript) (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - The Flame of Liberty by Ed Ainsworth., (Carbon copy) (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - They Hitched Their Wagon to a Star Sapphire by Leon Surmelian., (Copy) (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Additional Work by Ed Ainsworth
    - The California Story: Historical Pageant--Spectacle In Commemoration Of The 100th Anniversary Of California Statehood by Jack Moffit and Ed Ainsworth, 1950. (Box 80, Folder 8)
      Both script and Hollywood Bowl program.
      (See also: Box 62)
    - Samples of Suggested Narration and Continuity for Centennial Historical Pageant Celebrating the 100th Anniversary Of California Statehood in the Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum., Bound copy. (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Painters of the Desert by Ed Ainsworth. (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Bloody Gold by Ed Ainsworth. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Golden Checker Board., (Carbon copy) (Box 81, Folder 2)
      Interspersed handwritten notes.
    - The Columbus Devise, unpublished manuscript by Ed Ainsworth and Katherine Ainsworth, For Katherine Ainsworth., undated.; (Typescript) (Box 81, Folder 3)
      (See also: Collection 1395 Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous material on the National Cowboy Hall of Fame and its founder Chester A. Reynolds. (Box 81, Folder 4-5)
      Clippings, newsletters, memoranda, organizational material, documents with reference to California's participation in founding the National Cowboy Hall of Fame, carbon copy of California and the Cowboy Hall of Fame by Ed Ainsworth, written for Westways, another copy of the same article with handwritten corrections, The National Cowboy Hall of Fame (carbon copy of typescript with handwritten corrections) by Ed Ainsworth written for the Los Angeles Times, an issue of Partners: A Magazine of Labor and Management (December 1951) containing a story on Chester A. Reynolds and typescript of a chapter entitled A Hot Iron on History's Hip on Chester A. Reynolds.
    - Cowboy Hall of Fame., Photographs. (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Manuscript of Jackets (Pen Pictures)., (Carbon copy) (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Memories on the City of Dreams by Ed Ainsworth,; Enchanted Pueblo by Ed Ainsworth,; and Five Acres of Heaven by Ed Ainsworth, 1959 1959 1955.; Printed copies. (Box 82, Folder 1)
      (See also: Box 84 folder 7 Correspondence on small tracts)
    - Material on Jacqueline Cochran Odlum's campaign for Congress,., 1956 (Box 82, Folder 2)
      Newspapers, photographs, schedules, endorsements of Mrs. Odlum, memos, correspondence and scripts for radio appearances provided by Ed Ainsworth.
  - Miscellaneous Materials
    - Wild West, 1903. (Box 82, Folder 3)
      Magazine containing stories and sketches of Western Life.
    - Western newspapers,., 1873-1956; (incomplete) (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Clippings on Juan Bautista de Anza, various publications on the West. (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Publications on California. (Box 83, Folder 1-4)
      Including October 1966 isue of Pomona Valley Historian (Ed Ainsworth is on the editorial board of this publication).
    - Publications in Spanish on Spain and Mexico. (Box 83, Folder 5-6)
    - Photographs: Early Airplanes, ca., 1909. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Earl Warren, undated. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified negatives. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Western Photographs. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Record Bear on view in Los Angeles County Museum. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Valley Chapter NAA Management Club, Sam Yorty, 1965.; Tape: (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Face the Nation, Sam Yorty, undated.; Tape: (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Paper on Migrant and Bracero Concerns, no author, undated.; (Carbon copy) (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Script on need for water, no author, undated.; (Mimeographed) (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Material on Condors and Audubon Society, 1964. (Box 84, Folder 3)
      (See also: Box 22)
    - Material on National Geographic Society and United Water Conservation District Sespe Creek Project--Fact Book, map, for water. (Box 84, Folder 3)
      (See also: Boxes 40-58)
    - Clipping on the Freedom of the Press. (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Preparatory material for trip to Mexico. (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence on small tracts. (Box 84, Folder 7)
      (See also: Box 82 folder 1)
    - Correspondence in connection with the Cowboy Hall of Fame. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Photo of Ed Ainsworth (owner of Desert Barnacle) and of Manchester Body of The Daily News and of Earl Coffman, owner of Desert Inn. (Box 88)
      (See also oversize package 8)
    - Photo of Troy Kinney inscribed to Carl Oscar Borg, 1914. (Box 88)
    - Dinner menu aboard SS Lurline, undated. (Box 88)
    - 5 de Mayo 1862-1962., Poster: (Box 88)
    - American Indian Calendar, Mexican Historical Calendar Poster of Buddha, Christmas Etching., 1975. 1975. (Box 88)
    - Travel Posters of Britain. (Box 88)
    - Desert Barnacle., 1945-1947; (incomplete) (Box 89, Box 90)
      A paper published in Mecca, California, owned by Ed Ainsworth.
    - Departure of the Swallows. San Juan Capistrano, 1937.; (33 1/3 RPM record) (Box 98)
- Seven Scrapbooks Containing Clippings of Ed Ainsworth's Columns to Los Angeles Times, 1960-1967
  - 1960. (Box 91)
  - 1961. (Box 92)
  - 1962. (Box 93)
  - 1963. (Box 94)
  - 1964. (Box 95)
  - January 1, 1965-May 31, 1966. (Box 96)
  - June 2, 1966-June 11, 1967. (Box 96)
    Contains report on retirement part for Ed Ainsworth in Among Ourselves, publication of Los Angeles Times staff.
  - Unidentified motion picture strip. (Box 97)
  - Motion picture strip of Freedom's Shores. (Box 97)
    Ed Ainsworth collaborated on writing and production of this work.
    (See also: Box 79 folders 4-9)